<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Scripting on Aiden Arnkels-Webb</title>
    <link>https://aidenwebb.com/tags/scripting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scripting on Aiden Arnkels-Webb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>@ Aiden Arnkels-Webb</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 14:45:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aidenwebb.com/tags/scripting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cve-2023-23397 - Quickly Check Vulnerability Status and Trigger Updates</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/cve-2023-23397-quickly-check-vulnerability-status-and-trigger-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 14:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/cve-2023-23397-quickly-check-vulnerability-status-and-trigger-updates/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday Microsoft announced a new critical vulnerability CVE-2023-23397, a vulnerability in Microsoft Outlook that allows a threat actor to harvest NTLMv2 hashes via a specifically crafted Outlook appointment.
Microsoft state that attackers can exploit this vulnerability by sending an email that triggers automatically when it is retrieved and processed by the Outlook client. This can lead to exploitation BEFORE the email is viewed in the Preview Pane.
They also state that this vulnerability is being actively exploited in the wild.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to recusively apply NTFS permissions faster using PowerShell multithreading jobs</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/how-to-recusively-apply-ntfs-permissions-faster-using-powershell-multithreading-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 14:49:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/how-to-recusively-apply-ntfs-permissions-faster-using-powershell-multithreading-jobs/</guid>
      <description>Do you relate to the cover photo? Have your NTFS permissions just bombed out and you can&amp;rsquo;t bare the idea of waiting hours or days for your new permissions to apply?
Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I&amp;rsquo;m here to help.
It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that applying NTFS permissions to any directory tree larger than a few thousand files quickly decends in to a painstaking waiting game. The built in UI is garbage, and icacls is decent but single-threaded and slow.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
