<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Aiden Arnkels-Webb</title>
    <link>https://aidenwebb.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Aiden Arnkels-Webb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 12:36:29 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aidenwebb.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the difference between Authentication, Authorisation and Accounting? (AAA)</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.github.io/posts/2022/07/whats-the-difference-between-authentication-authorisation-and-accounting-aaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 12:36:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.github.io/posts/2022/07/whats-the-difference-between-authentication-authorisation-and-accounting-aaa/</guid>
      <description>Authentication Authentication is saying &amp;ldquo;I am me&amp;rdquo;. It validates who you are. When you go to a club and the bouncer stops you and you tell him you&amp;rsquo;re on the guest list, you then show him your ID and he says &amp;ldquo;Ahh! You&amp;rsquo;re that guy, come on in&amp;rdquo; - that&amp;rsquo;s Authentication
Authorisation Authorisation validates what you claim to be. Going back to the club and the bouncer stops you. You show him your ID.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Remove Submodule</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.github.io/posts/2022/07/git-remove-submodule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 09:51:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.github.io/posts/2022/07/git-remove-submodule/</guid>
      <description>Submodules aren&amp;rsquo;t removed using git rm submodule-dir, they need to be removed in a far more thorough and annoying fashion. There are a number of unclear explainations at various sources so I decided to write my own findings.
Delete the relevant parts from the .gitmodules file. EG: [submodule &amp;#34;blog/themes/PaperMod&amp;#34;] path = blog/themes/PaperMod url = https://github.com/adityatelange/hugo-PaperMod.git Stage .gitmodules via git add .gitmodules Remove the relevant parts from .git/config EG: [submodule &amp;#34;blog/themes/PaperMod&amp;#34;] url = https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving my blog to Hugo - Getting started with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.github.io/posts/2022/07/moving-my-blog-to-hugo-getting-started-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 22:01:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.github.io/posts/2022/07/moving-my-blog-to-hugo-getting-started-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I recently came to the conclusion that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t posting on my blog nearly as much as I&amp;rsquo;d like to. My blog runs on wordpress, and I&amp;rsquo;ve felt for a while that the process of logging in, creating a post, fixing formatting in a WSYWGI editor and eventually posting was too much resistance when I commonly just write notes in plain text. So, why not just write posts in plain text and have something else do the work of turning that in to a post or a blog?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Hard Link Azure AD Connect On Prem Users to Azure AD Office 365 Accounts</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.github.io/posts/2022/03/how-to-hard-link-azure-ad-connect-on-prem-users-to-azure-ad-office-365-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 10:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.github.io/posts/2022/03/how-to-hard-link-azure-ad-connect-on-prem-users-to-azure-ad-office-365-accounts/</guid>
      <description>The Problem You&amp;rsquo;ve set up Azure AD Connect or Azure AD Connect Cloud Sync, but some users haven&amp;rsquo;t sync&amp;rsquo;d correctly. Trying to force a new sync / Soft Link based on SMTP or UPN matching doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. These sync&amp;rsquo;d users may have created new Azure AD accounts, or may have failed to create an Azure AD account altogether. Your internal users UPN matches a domain configured in Azure AD.
The Cause The initial soft link matches on UPN or SMTP, but may fail if there are conflicting ProxyAddresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix Server 2019 Activation Error: Run “slui.exe 0x2a 0xC004F069”</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.github.io/posts/2021/03/how-to-fix-server-2019-activation-error-run-slui.exe-0x2a-0xc004f069/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 13:17:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.github.io/posts/2021/03/how-to-fix-server-2019-activation-error-run-slui.exe-0x2a-0xc004f069/</guid>
      <description>The Problem You&amp;rsquo;re unable to activate a copy of Windows Server 2019 Evaluation edition with your VLSC MAK key
The Cause Server 2019 Evaluation edition can only be activated with a retail key. This must happen before a Volume Licence Key can be used.
The Fix We need to use DISM to change the product version/edition
Open an elevated command prompt
Get a list of available version upgrade paths by typing:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fix SB_BLOCK_NOT_PRESENT error in Veeam</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.github.io/posts/2020/11/how-to-fix-sb_block_not_present-error-in-veeam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 18:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.github.io/posts/2020/11/how-to-fix-sb_block_not_present-error-in-veeam/</guid>
      <description>The Problem Veeam is failing to back up one of your Hyper-V VM&amp;rsquo;s and is throwing the error: VHDx:CVhdxDisk.InitialValidation: Invalid bitmap block (all bitmap block of fixed and dynamic disks must be in SB_BLOCK_NOT_PRESENT state) Agent failed to process method {VHDx.GetDiskInformation}
The Cause The error is telling us that Veeam&amp;rsquo;s VHDx InitialValidation function failed as the VHDx had blocks in an invalid state.
According to Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s OpenSpecs Documentation for VHDx, the only valid Sector Bitmap Block state for fixed and dynamic disks is SB_BLOCK_NOT_PRESENT</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traps and Dangers of Unmanaged Incidents and How to Solve Them</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.github.io/posts/2020/09/traps-and-dangers-of-unmanaged-incidents-and-how-to-solve-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 17:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.github.io/posts/2020/09/traps-and-dangers-of-unmanaged-incidents-and-how-to-solve-them/</guid>
      <description>Introduction ITIL defines an incident as “an unplanned interruption to or quality reduction of an IT service”.
In order to minimise disruption caused by an incident and restore normal service as quickly as possible, it&amp;rsquo;s vital to have an efficient incident management process. Unfortunately, this is something a lot of IT teams get wrong.
Unmanaged Incidents It&amp;rsquo;s 1 PM and your team has just started receiving calls from one of your users that the network drives are down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comment Policy</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.github.io/comment-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.github.io/comment-policy/</guid>
      <description>comment policy</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
