<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Aiden Arnkels-Webb</title>
    <link>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Aiden Arnkels-Webb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>@ Aiden Arnkels-Webb</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 10:48:32 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aidenwebb.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning C# - Building a MUD Part 1</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/learning-c-sharp-building-a-mud-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 10:48:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/learning-c-sharp-building-a-mud-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Headnotes First, the project link, for those of you who just want to gander at code and commit history
Second, this post uses some Mermaid JS graphs, which don&amp;rsquo;t look great on a dark background, so I recommend switching the site to light mode by clicking the little sun next to &amp;ldquo;Home&amp;rdquo; in the navbar.
Introduction Last night was one of the worst night&amp;rsquo;s sleep I&amp;rsquo;ve had in the past few years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping Packlist</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/camping-packlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 08:38:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/camping-packlist/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;m off to Me&amp;rsquo;ra Luna in a few days! This is my first time camping since the Covid pandemic and thankfully I uncovered a previous camping packing list. I figure I may as well share it here for easy finding in future and so others may find it useful. Bring on the festival!
A place to rest Tent Tent Pegs Mallet Mattress Air Mattress pump Sleeping bag Pillow Folding chair Torch Look after yourself Clothes Wet weather clothes / spare shoes / boots / rain coat Toothbrush / Toothpaste / Floss Shower Gel Painkillers Sun Cream Sun Glasses Condoms Wet Wipes Cutlery / Plates / Mess Tins / Mug Food Water Bottle(s) Towel First Aid kit Toilet roll Thermals / Sleeping clothes Deodrant Tick removers Sanitary towels / tampons (even for guys, they come in handy often!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the difference between Authentication, Authorisation and Accounting? (AAA)</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/whats-the-difference-between-authentication-authorisation-and-accounting-aaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 12:36:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/whats-the-difference-between-authentication-authorisation-and-accounting-aaa/</guid>
      <description>Authentication Authentication is saying &amp;ldquo;I am me&amp;rdquo;. It validates who you are. When you go to a club and the bouncer stops you and you tell him you&amp;rsquo;re on the guest list, you then show him your ID and he says &amp;ldquo;Ahh! You&amp;rsquo;re that guy, come on in&amp;rdquo; - that&amp;rsquo;s Authentication
Authorisation Authorisation validates what you claim to be. Going back to the club and the bouncer stops you. You show him your ID.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Remove Submodule</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/git-remove-submodule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 09:51:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/git-remove-submodule/</guid>
      <description>Submodules aren&amp;rsquo;t removed using git rm submodule-dir, they need to be removed in a far more thorough and annoying fashion. There are a number of unclear explanations at various sources so I decided to write my own findings.
Delete the relevant parts from the .gitmodules file.
EG:
1 2 3 [submodule &amp;#34;blog/themes/PaperMod&amp;#34;] path = blog/themes/PaperMod url = https://github.com/adityatelange/hugo-PaperMod.git Stage .gitmodules via git add .gitmodules
Remove the relevant parts from .git/config</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving my blog to Hugo - Getting started with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/moving-my-blog-to-hugo-getting-started-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 22:01:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/moving-my-blog-to-hugo-getting-started-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I recently came to the conclusion that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t posting on my blog nearly as much as I&amp;rsquo;d like to. My blog runs on WordPress, and I&amp;rsquo;ve felt for a while that the process of logging in, creating a post, fixing formatting in a WSYWGI editor and eventually posting was too much resistance when I commonly just write notes in plain text. So, why not just write posts in plain text and have something else do the work of turning that in to a post or a blog?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Hard Link Azure AD Connect On Prem Users to Azure AD Office 365 Accounts</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/how-to-hard-link-azure-ad-connect-on-prem-users-to-azure-ad-office-365-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 10:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/how-to-hard-link-azure-ad-connect-on-prem-users-to-azure-ad-office-365-accounts/</guid>
      <description>The Problem You&amp;rsquo;ve set up Azure AD Connect or Azure AD Connect Cloud Sync, but some users haven&amp;rsquo;t sync&amp;rsquo;d correctly. Trying to force a new sync / Soft Link based on SMTP or UPN matching doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. These sync&amp;rsquo;d users may have created new Azure AD accounts, or may have failed to create an Azure AD account altogether. Your internal users UPN matches a domain configured in Azure AD.
The Cause The initial soft link matches on UPN or SMTP, but may fail if there are conflicting ProxyAddresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix Server 2019 Activation Error: Run “slui.exe 0x2a 0xC004F069”</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/how-to-fix-server-2019-activation-error-run-slui.exe-0x2a-0xc004f069/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 13:17:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/how-to-fix-server-2019-activation-error-run-slui.exe-0x2a-0xc004f069/</guid>
      <description>The Problem You&amp;rsquo;re unable to activate a copy of Windows Server 2019 Evaluation edition with your VLSC MAK key
The Cause Server 2019 Evaluation edition can only be activated with a retail key. This must happen before a Volume Licence Key can be used.
The Fix We need to use DISM to change the product version/edition
Open an elevated command prompt
Get a list of available version upgrade paths by typing:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fix SB_BLOCK_NOT_PRESENT error in Veeam</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/how-to-fix-sb_block_not_present-error-in-veeam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 18:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/how-to-fix-sb_block_not_present-error-in-veeam/</guid>
      <description>The Problem Veeam is failing to back up one of your Hyper-V VM&amp;rsquo;s and is throwing the error: VHDx:CVhdxDisk.InitialValidation: Invalid bitmap block (all bitmap block of fixed and dynamic disks must be in SB_BLOCK_NOT_PRESENT state) Agent failed to process method {VHDx.GetDiskInformation}
The Cause The error is telling us that Veeam&amp;rsquo;s VHDx InitialValidation function failed as the VHDx had blocks in an invalid state.
According to Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s OpenSpecs Documentation for VHDx, the only valid Sector Bitmap Block state for fixed and dynamic disks is SB_BLOCK_NOT_PRESENT</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traps and Dangers of Unmanaged Incidents and How to Solve Them</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/traps-and-dangers-of-unmanaged-incidents-and-how-to-solve-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 17:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/traps-and-dangers-of-unmanaged-incidents-and-how-to-solve-them/</guid>
      <description>Introduction ITIL defines an incident as “an unplanned interruption to or quality reduction of an IT service”.
In order to minimise disruption caused by an incident and restore normal service as quickly as possible, it&amp;rsquo;s vital to have an efficient incident management process. Unfortunately, this is something a lot of IT teams get wrong.
Unmanaged Incidents It&amp;rsquo;s 1 PM and your team has just started receiving calls from one of your users that the network drives are down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to check if your CPU supports Virtualisation</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/how-to-check-if-your-cpu-supports-virtualisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 13:42:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/how-to-check-if-your-cpu-supports-virtualisation/</guid>
      <description>Check Task Manager The first, simplest option to check is to open task manager. Click the performance tab Check if Virtualisation is Enabled If Virtualisation is not Enabled, this could be due to it being disabled in the BIOS. Before enabling it, check if your processor is compatible.
Check Processor Compatibility Identify your Processor Press the Windows Key Type &amp;ldquo;System Information&amp;rdquo; in the search box Make a note of your processor make and model Check Product Specs - Intel: If your processor is Intel, go to the Intel Product Specification Page and look up your processor model and open the specification page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fix QNAP NAS web GUI interface timing out or never loading</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/how-to-fix-qnap-nas-web-gui-interface-timing-out-or-never-loading/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 20:55:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/how-to-fix-qnap-nas-web-gui-interface-timing-out-or-never-loading/</guid>
      <description>The Problem You&amp;rsquo;re trying to connect to your NAS&amp;rsquo;s web interface but it&amp;rsquo;s just spinning forever and not actually loading.
The Cause The cause can be a number of things, but it boils down to an issue with the http service or proxy service on the QNAP.
Sometimes a configuration problem will cause the service to behave badly. A firmware update may cause a mismatch between the config file and the service being run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why “traverse folder” and “execute file” is a combined NTFS permission</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/why-traverse-folder-and-execute-file-is-a-combined-ntfs-permission/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 13:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/why-traverse-folder-and-execute-file-is-a-combined-ntfs-permission/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked why the Advanced Permissions dialogue on NTFS folders lists &amp;ldquo;Traverse folder / execute file&amp;rdquo; as one single permission.
On the surface it seems counterintuitive that you&amp;rsquo;d allow a user to navigate through a folder, or execute its contents.
There&amp;rsquo;s no official Microsoft documentation on the design decisions, however, from a filesystem perspective, entering a folder is the same as executing or running it. The same is true of 3 classic Unix filesystem flags and permissions, where the &amp;ldquo;X&amp;rdquo; flag allows both directory traversal and file execution, while &amp;ldquo;R&amp;rdquo; allows reading and &amp;ldquo;W&amp;rdquo; allows writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to enable/disable hardware devices using Windows Powershell</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/how-to-enable/disable-hardware-devices-using-windows-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 22:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/how-to-enable/disable-hardware-devices-using-windows-powershell/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re working on Windows Server Core or remotely on another computer and don&amp;rsquo;t have access to the Windows GUI, you might have trouble disabling a faulty or unwanted plug-and-play device. Thankfully PowerShell makes it easy to get, enable and disable devices in Device Manager using Get-PnpDevice, Enable-PnpDevice and Disable-PnpDevice
How to query devices 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 Get-PnpDevice # Get&amp;#39;s all PNP Devices Get-PnpDevice -PresentOnly # Gets all PNP Devices currently attached or physically present in the system Get-PnpDevice -FriendlyName &amp;#34;*Ethernet*&amp;#34; # Gets all PNP Devices with a name containing &amp;#34;Ethernet&amp;#34; Get-PnpDevice -Status ERROR # Gets all PNP Devices in an errored states How to enable or disable devices To enable disable a device, simply pipe the output of Get-PnpDevice to Disable-PnpDevice or Enable-PnpDevice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fix conflicting proxy addresses in O365 when creating a mailbox</title>
      <link>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/how-to-fix-conflicting-proxy-addresses-in-o365-when-creating-a-mailbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 01:11:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aidenwebb.com/posts/how-to-fix-conflicting-proxy-addresses-in-o365-when-creating-a-mailbox/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to fix conflicting proxy addresses in Office / Exchange 365</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
